# PRAVEEN KUMAR RAJKUMAR (1) Featured

Senior Associate seeking roles in Software Development, Application
Programming, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Project Management, Release
Management, Client Management, Incident Management, Shell Scripting, Unix, SQL



Current Designation: Senior Associate - IT Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: JP MORGAN CHASE & CO. Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]

Pref. Location: United Arab Emirates (UAE), Chennai, INDIA Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Associate, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Technical Architecture, Project Management, Release Management, Client Management, Incident

Management, Shell Scripting, Unix, SQL

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

## Summary

9+ Years of Overall Experience in the IT Industry.

Proven knowledge in supporting Trade Management Applications - Especially in Equity Swaps and P&L Calculations.

Excellent knowledge on ITIL processes including incident management, problem management, change and release management

Exposure in handling Traders and Middle Office Users across all regions.

Solid experience in Handling Migration Projects and Developing Support Teams from

Scratch. Managed Support Teams in India and Buenos Aires.

Strong Knowledge in Unix, Shell Scripting and SQL.

Strong Experience is Supporting Applications that connect to exchanges to get Market Information.

# **Work Experience**

JP MORGAN CHASE & CO. as Senior Associate - IT

Jun 2015 to Till Date

Lead of the Equities and Derivatives Trade Management Support for America Region. Trade Management applications include Trade booking System, Trade Processing Applications, Risk and PnL calculation applications and Settlement Systems. Developed an application support team in Buenos Aires that provided support services to global equity swaps market

traders based in the U.S. and Europe

Resolve both Technical and Functional Issues across Life Cycle

of the Trade like Booking, Settlement and PnL

Interact with the regional Support Team and setup a strong Global Support Team

Perform detailed analysis on production problem, engage and coordinate with different teams for resolution

Support and Enhance the application the Manages Reference

Data and gets prices from exchanges.

Setup Chat Bot, Reporting Tool and Workstation Tools to reduce support efforts.

### **SOCIETE GENERALE** as Senior System Engineer Dec 2013 to Jun 2015

Evaluating client's requirements and then proposing adequate

and effective solutions.

Change management process to ensure standardized methods and procedures are used for efficient and prompt handling of all changes.

Creating new Shell scripts and Stored Procedures to Add New or Enhance existing application functionality. Control-Management, this includes creating new jobs and updating the existing jobs to meet the requirements. Support the project team by actively participating in the research and resolution of Production issues Providing L3 Support to the Banking Application, Ensure that the application tasks complete successfully without any delay

### TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES LIMITED as System Engineer

Nov 2010 to Dec 2013

or failure.

A Development/Enhancement project that included 4 applications for the Client CITI Bank. Application front end was developed in PowerBuilder.

Analyzing the Clients requirements and preparing the Project Plan and Design

Documents for each enhancement and getting clients approval. Developing the Application, that includes writing PowerBuilder scripts, creating new Stored Procedures/tables in database and writing shell scripts and C++ programs in the Unix Server.

Performing Unit Testing, Integration Testing and Regression Testing. Interacting with the clients to perform UAT and documenting their comments.

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from CMR institute of technology in 2010

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Canada	Expert			
Tamil	Expert			

### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time